Guide to the Charles Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, 1918-(1924-1928)-1963; Series II; 13'9" (40 boxes)
  - Books
    - The Intimate Papers of Colonel House Volumes III and IV
      - First draft, Volume III, Chapters 12-15 (Box 32, Folder 69)
      - First draft, Volume III, Chapters 16-19 (Box 32, Folder 70)
      - First draft, Volume III, Chapters 20-23 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - First draft, Volume III, Chapters 24-25 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Second draft, Volume III, Chapters 1-4 (Box 33, Folder 73)
      - Second draft, Volume III, Chapters 5-8 (Box 33, Folder 74)
      - Second draft, Volume III, Chapters 9-11 (Box 33, Folder 75)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume III, Chapters 1-3 (Box 34, Folder 76)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume III, Chapters 4-7 (Box 34, Folder 77)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume III, Chapters 8-10 (Box 34, Folder 78)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume III, Chapters 11-14 (Box 34, Folder 79)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume IV, Chapters 1-4 (Box 34, Folder 80)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume IV, Chapters 5-7 (Box 35, Folder 81)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume IV, Chapters 8-10 (Box 35, Folder 82)
      - Second draft, revised, Volume IV, Chapters 11-14 (Box 35, Folder 83)
      - Third draft, Volume III, Chapters 1-4 (Box 36, Folder 84)
      - Third draft, Volume III, Chapters 5-8 (Box 36, Folder 85)
      - Third draft, Volume III, Chapters 9-12 (Box 36, Folder 86)
      - Third draft, Volume III, Chapters 13-14 (Box 36, Folder 87)
      - Third draft, Volume IV, Chapters 1-4 (Box 36, Folder 88)
      - Third draft, Volume IV, Chapters 5-7 (Box 36, Folder 89)
      - Third draft, Volume IV, Chapters 8-10 (Box 37, Folder 90)
      - Third draft, Volume IV, Chapters 11-12 (Box 37, Folder 91)
      - Third draft, Volume IV, Chapters 13-14 (Box 37, Folder 92)
    - The Intimate Papers of Colonel House (Related Material)
      - Permission files - general (Box 38, Folder 93)
      - Permission files, A - B (Box 38, Folder 94)
      - Permission files, C - F (Box 38, Folder 95)
      - Permission files, G - K (Box 38, Folder 96)
      - Permission files, L - M (Box 38, Folder 97)
      - Permission files, N - P (Box 38, Folder 98)
      - Permission files, R - W (Box 38, Folder 99)
      - Acknowledgments from various libraries for complimentary copies (Box 38, Folder 100)
      - Press Releases (Box 39, Folder 101)
      - Advertising - printed (Box 39, Folder 102)
      - Advertising - newspaper (Box 39, Folder 103)
      - Newspaper promotion, January 1926 (Box 40, Folder 104-107)
      - Newspaper promotion, February 1926 (Box 40, Folder 108-110)
      - Newspaper promotion (foreign clippings), February 1926 (Box 40, Folder 111)
      - Reviews (clippings), March 1926 (Box 41, Folder 112-118)
      - Reviews (clippings), March 1926 (Box 42, Folder 119-122)
      - Reviews (clippings), April 1926 (Box 42, Folder 123-125)
      - Reviews (clippings), May 1926 (Box 42, Folder 126)
      - Reviews (clippings), June 1926 (Box 42, Folder 127)
      - Reviews (clippings), July - December 1926 (Box 42, Folder 128)
      - Reviews (clippings), January, April 1927 (Box 43, Folder 129)
      - Reviews (clippings), October 1928 (Box 43, Folder 130)
      - Reviews (clippings), November - December 1928 (Box 43, Folder 131)
      - Reviews (clippings), January - March, November 1929 (Box 43, Folder 132)
      - Reviews (clippings), 1931-1933 (Box 43, Folder 133)
      - Reviews (clippings), miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 134-135)
    - Letters from the Paris Peace Conference
      - Letters A - C, 1918 December 4-16 (Box 44, Folder 136)
      - Letters D - G, 1918 December 20-29 (Box 44, Folder 137)
      - Letters H - T, 1919 January (Box 44, Folder 138)
      - Memorandum of conversation with Ion Bratianu, 1919 January 31 (Box 44, Folder 139)
      - Letters U - X, 1919 February (Box 44, Folder 139)
      - Letters Y - CC, 1919 March-April (Box 44, Folder 140)
      - Letters DD - GG, 1919 May (Box 44, Folder 141)
      - Letters HH - LL, 1919 June (Box 44, Folder 142)
      - Notes concerning conference with Woodrow Wilson on board George Washington (Box 44, Folder 143)
      - Orders permitting travel in Belgium, 1919 June 7 (Box 44, Folder 144)
      - Memoranda written on U. S. S. George Washington, 1919 July 2 (Box 44, Folder 145)
      - Memorabilia of voyage on U. S. S. George Washington, 1918 December (Box 44, Folder 146)
      - Memorabilia of voyage on U. S. S. George Washington, 1919 July (Box 44, Folder 147)
      - Book format and pagination, undated (Box 44, Folder 148)
      - Working materials (Box 44, Folder 149)
      - December letters with revisions (Box 44, Folder 150)
      - January letters with revisions (Box 44, Folder 151)
      - February - April letters with revisions (Box 44, Folder 152)
      - May - June letters with revisions (Box 44, Folder 153)
      - Manuscript of "Foreword" by H. B. Whiteman, Jr. (Box 45, Folder 154)
      - Manuscript of "Introduction" by Charles Seymour (Box 45, Folder 155)
      - Manuscript of Chapter 1: "Crossing the Atlantic" (Box 45, Folder 156)
      - Manuscript of Chapter 2: "The Paris Scene in December" (Box 45, Folder 157)
      - Manuscript of Chapter 3: "Waiting for the Conference to Begin" (Box 45, Folder 158)
      - Manuscript of Chapter 4: "The Conference Commences" (Box 45, Folder 159)
      - Manuscript of Chapter 5: "End of the First phase" (1 page) (Box 45, Folder 160)
      - Illustrations (Box 45, Folder 161)
      - Maps (Box 45, Folder 162)
      - Index manuscript (Box 45, Folder 163)
      - Proofs of title page and table of contents (Box 45, Folder 164)
      - Printer's proofs (Box 45, Folder 165-166)
      - Extra copies of Charles Seymour's Diary Letters from Paris Peace Conference, 1918 December-1919 June (Box 46, Folder 167-170)
    - Miscellaneous books
      - La Politique de Wilson et le Sénat. Revue de l'Institut de Sociologie II, 1 (January 1925), pp. 1-19., 1919 (Box 47, Folder 171)
      - Chapter V of Chronicles of America, 1920 (Box 47, Folder 171a)
      - Re: What Really Happened at Paris, 1921 (Box 47, Folder 172)
      - Printer's proofs of final chapter of American Neutrality: 1914-1917, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 173)
      - Geography, Justice, & Politics at the Paris Conference of 1919, 1951 (Box 47, Folder 173a)
  - Contributions to Books
    - "Warren G. Harding." Encyclopedia Britannica (1926). (Box 48, Folder 174)
    - "Woodrow Wilson." Dictionary of American Biography (1937). (Box 48, Folder 175)
    - Biographical note: Col. House. National Cyclopaedia of American Biography (1938 Oct 22) (Box 48, Folder 175a)
    - "Defense for America" in book to be published by Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies. (1940 Jun 11) (Box 48, Folder 175b)
    - "Edward M. House." Who Was Who in America (1943). (Box 48, Folder 176)
    - "The Search for a Faculty," in Seventy-Five: A Study of a Generation in Transition. Yale Daily News (1953). (Box 48, Folder 177)
    - "Edward Mandell House." Dictionary of American Biography (1955). (Box 48, Folder 178)
    - Preface to A Crossroads of Freedom: The 1912 Campaign Speeches of Woodrow Wilson. Edited by John W. Davidson (1956). (Box 48, Folder 179)
    - "Edward Mandell House." Collier's Encyclopedia vol. 12 (1960), pp. 303-304. (Box 48, Folder 180)
    - "William Howard Taft." Encyclopedia Britannica (1960). (Box 48, Folder 181)
    - "(Thomas) Woodrow Wilson." Encyclopedia Britannica (1961). (Box 48, Folder 182)
    - "The House-Bernstorff Conversations in Perspective," in Studies in Diplomatic History and Historiography. Edited by A. O. Sarkissian; typescript and draft (1961). (Box 48, Folder 183)
    - "The House-Bernstorff Conversations in Perspective," in Studies in Diplomatic History and Historiography. Edited by A. O. Sarkissian; outline, carbon copies of House-Bernstorff notes, draft (1961). (Box 48, Folder 184)
    - "The House-Bernstorff Conversations in Perspective," in Studies in Diplomatic History and Historiography. Edited by A. O. Sarkissian; miscellaneous early drafts (1961). (Box 48, Folder 185)
    - Bibliographical Note: Woodrow Wilson. Dictionary of American Biography (1962). (Box 48, Folder 186)
    - "Edward Mandell House." Encyclopedia Britannica (no date) (Box 48, Folder 187)
  - Articles
    - "English Undergraduate Life" (De Forest Prize Essay). Yale Alumni Weekly (May 1908), p. 787. (Box 49, Folder 188)
    - "The Position of Italy." New Haven Journal-Courier (September 7, 1914). (Box 49, Folder 189)
    - "The Neutrality of Belgium." New Haven Journal-Courier (September 8, 1914). (Box 49, Folder 190)
    - "The Revolt of Europe." New Haven Journal-Courier (September 28, 1914). (Box 49, Folder 191)
    - "Recent Aspects of British Electoral Reform." History Teacher's Magazine VI, 3 (March 1915), pp. 70-73. (Box 49, Folder 192)
    - "Study of History." Yale Daily News (April 13, 1916). (Box 49, Folder 193)
    - "The Perils of Failure." " Made in Connecticut" Interviews on the World War (c. 1917), p. 13 (Box 49, Folder 194)
    - "The Alleged Isolation of Germany." Yale Review VI, 3 (April 1917), pp. 521-535. (Box 49, Folder 195)
    - "The League of Nations." Yale Review IX, 1 (October 1919), pp. 27-43. (Box 49, Folder 196)
    - "The Struggle for the Adriatic." Yale Review IX, 3 (April 1920), pp. 462-481. (Box 49, Folder 197)
    - "The League of Nations." The Volume Library (c. 1921), pp. 92-93. (Box 49, Folder 198)
    - "President Wilson at Paris." Pacific Review I (March 1921), pp. 569-575. (Box 49, Folder 199)
    - "Mr. Tumulty as Historian." Trend Vol. 1 no. 4 (1921 Dec 21) (Box 49, Folder 199a)
    - "French Policy and American Opinion." Yale Review XI, 3 (April 1922), pp. 479-495. (Box 49, Folder 200)
    - "America's Duty to Europe Today." Current History XIX, 2 (November 1923), pp. 195-201. (Box 49, Folder 201)
    - "War-Time Relations of America and Great Britain." Atlantic Monthly CXXXIII (May 1924), pp. 669-677. (Box 49, Folder 202)
    - "America's Responsibility to Germany." Atlantic Monthly CXXXIII (June 1924), pp. 824-832. (Box 49, Folder 203)
    - Le Mouvement ouvrier an début de la Monarchie de juillet (1830-1834) by Octave Festy. Yale Review (old series) XVIII, 2 (August 1909), pp. 218-219. (Box 49, Folder 204)
    - "The Beginning of the Peace." Yale Review XV, 2 (January 1926), pp. 209-224. (Box 49, Folder 205)
    - "Refighting the War on Paper." Yale Review XVIII, 4 (June 1929), pp. 625-645. (Box 49, Folder 206)
    - "Imaginative Courage: An Editorial." Outlook and Independent CLIII (October 9, 1929), p. 221. (Box 49, Folder 207)
    - "Diplomatic Background of America's Entry into the War." Current History XXXIII, 4 (January 1931). (Box 49, Folder 208)
    - "The New Yale." Review of Reviews (June 1931), pp. 44-45. (Box 49, Folder 209)
    - "The New Colleges at Yale." Yale Literary Magazine (November 1931), pp. 10-21. (reprinted from Princeton Alumni Weekly ) (Box 49, Folder 210)
    - "How Yale's House Plan Works." Banta's Greek Exchange (October 1932), pp. 301-303. (Box 49, Folder 211)
    - "Oberst House, ein Kapitel Amerikanischer Europolitik." Die Neue Rundschau XLIV (June 1933), pp. 757-767. (Box 49, Folder 212)
    - "Kolonel House." Wetenschappelijke Bladen (April 1, 1934), pp. 74-90. (Dutch reprint of article in Die Neue Rundschau June 1933) (Box 49, Folder 213)
    - "American Neutrality: The Experience of 1914-1917." Foreign Affairs XIV (October 1935), pp. 3-13. (Box 49, Folder 214)
    - "The End of Locarno." Yale Alumni Weekly XLV (March 20, 1936), p. 5. (Box 49, Folder 215)
    - Czechoslovakia. Yale Daily News (1938 Oct 10). (Box 49, Folder 215a)
    - "L'evolution de l'education americaine." Le Temps (1939 Jul 21), p. 20. (Box 49, Folder 215b)
    - "Czechoslovak Frontiers." Yale Review (1939 winter), pp. 273-291. (Box 49, Folder 215c)
    - "How Many Courses Make an Education?" Yale Banner (1939) (Box 49, Folder 216)
    - "Awakening to Importance of Defending the Democratic Way of Life." The Boston Herald (1940 Jun 30). (Box 49, Folder 216a)
    - "Responsibility and Privilege in a Democracy." Yale Alumni Magazine (1940 Sep 27), p.9. (Box 49, Folder 217)
    - "War's Impact on the Campus." The New York Times Magazine (1940 Sep 29). (Box 49, Folder 217a)
    - "Letter to the Editor." The Cambridge Review (1941 Feb 14), pp. 253-254. (Box 49, Folder 218)
    - "What is the stake for Americans in the field of education in the present world crisis?" American Mercury (1941 Oct 20). (Box 49, Folder 218a)
    - "How Free Can Speech Be in Time of War?" The New York Times Magazine (1942 Apr 12). (Box 49, Folder 218b)
    - "The College Becomes a 'Task Force'." The New York Times Magazine (1942 Sep 6), pp. 3, 26. (Box 49, Folder 218c)
    - "Challenge, and Opportunity, for the College." The New York Times Magazine (1942 Dec 27), p. 7. (Box 49, Folder 218)
    - "Challenge and Opportunity for the College." The Magazine of Sigma Chi (February-March 1943), pp. 17-19. (Box 49, Folder 219)
    - "Versailles in Perspective." Virginia Quarterly Review XIX, 4 (October 1943), early draft. (Box 49, Folder 220)
    - "Compulsary Military Training? Yes." Educational Record XXXI, 1 (January 1945), pp. 9-16. Also, Reprint in Liberty Magazine (March 28, 1945), p. 22. (Box 49, Folder 221)
    - "America and National Security." New Haven Teacher's Journal XXXIX, 1 (Fall, 1945), pp. 9-10, 29-33. (Box 49, Folder 222)
    - "Policy and Personality at the Paris Peace Conference." Virginia Quarterly Review XXI, 4 (October 1945), pp. 517-534. (Box 49, Folder 223)
    - "Study of Hebrew Was Once Required at Yale." The Bulletin (West New York Jewish Community Center, October 1949). (Box 49, Folder 224)
    - Comment on "Report of the President's Committee on General Education." Yale Daily News (c. October 1953). (Box 49, Folder 225)
    - "Woodrow Wilson in Perspective." Foreign Affairs XXXII, 2 (January 1956), pp. 175-186. (Box 49, Folder 226)
    - "Woodrow Wilson in Perspective." Foreign Affairs XXXII, 2 (January 1956), drafts. (Box 49, Folder 227)
    - "Woodrow Wilson in Perspective," Foreign Affairs XXXII, 2 (January 1956), drafts. (Box 49, Folder 228)
    - "Woodrow Wilson in Perspective," Foreign Affairs XXXII, 2 (January 1956), notes. (Box 49, Folder 229)
    - "The Paris Education of Woodrow Wilson." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXII, 4 (October 1956), pp. 578-593. (Box 50, Folder 230)
    - "The Paris Education of Woodrow Wilson." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXII, 4 (October 1956), notes. (Box 50, Folder 231)
    - "Woodrow Wilson: A Political Balance Sheet." Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society CI, 2 (April 1957), pp. 135-141. (Box 50, Folder 232)
    - "The Meaning of Freedom." The Meaning of Freedom Freedom Fund, Inc. (1958), pp. 41-43. (Box 50, Folder 233)
    - "The Basic Differences in an English Education." New York Herald Tribune Sunday Forum (January 29, 1961). (Box 50, Folder 234)
    - "Woodrow Wilson and Self-Determination in the Tyrol." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXVIII, 4 (October 1962). (Box 50, Folder 235)
    - "Woodrow Wilson and Self-Determination in the Tyrol." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXVIII, 4 (October 1962), related papers. (Box 50, Folder 236)
    - "Woodrow Wilson and Self-Determination in the Tyrol." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXVIII, 4 (October,1962), notes - 5x8 cards. (Box 50, Folder 237)
    - "Woodrow Wilson and Self-Determination in the Tyrol." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXVIII, 4 (October 1962), various drafts. (Box 50, Folder 238)
    - "Woodrow Wilson and Self-Determination in the Tyrol." Virginia Quarterly Review XXXVIII, 4 (October 1962), various drafts. (Box 50, Folder 239)
    - "End of a Friendship." American Heritage XIV, 5 (August 1963). (Box 50, Folder 240)
    - "End of a Friendship." American Heritage XIV, 5 (August 1963), typescript and miscellaneous papers. (Box 50, Folder 241)
    - "End of a Friendship." American Heritage XIV, 5 (August 1963), various drafts. (Box 50, Folder 242)
    - "End of a Friendship." American Heritage XIV, 5 (August 1963), miscellaneous papers. (Box 50, Folder 243)
    - "A Program of Collegiate Studies for Returning Service Men," _________, (no date). (Box 51, Folder 244)
    - "The Sixtus Affair." _________, (no date). (Box 51, Folder 245)
    - Statement on the retirement of Larry Tighe. _________, (no date). (Box 51, Folder 246)
    - Manuscript on Mountaineering, written for course "Essay Writing" given by Professor John M. Berdan, (1908), unpublished. (Box 51, Folder 247)
    - "Religious Life at Yale at the Turn of the Century." Unpublished? (no date) (Box 51, Folder 248)
    - "Willtown Bluff." Unpublished? no date (Box 51, Folder 249)
  - Memoranda of Conversations
    - Conversations with Colonel House, Index (Box 52, Folder 250)
    - Conversation with Woodrow Wilson, 1918 December 10 (Box 52, Folder 251)
    - Conversation with Colonel House, 1920 March 17 (Box 52, Folder 252)
    - Conversations with Colonel House, 1921 December - 1922 February (Box 52, Folder 253)
    - Conversation with Colonel House, 1922 March-November (Box 52, Folder 254-257)
    - Conversation with Sir William Wiseman, 1922 November 16 (Box 52, Folder 258)
    - Conversation with T. W. Gregory re: the Wilson Cabinet, 1923 May 11 (Box 52, Folder 259)
    - Conversations with Colonel House, 1924 January-February (Box 52, Folder 260)
    - Conversation with Colonel House re: Captain Bill McDonald (Box 52, Folder 261)
    - Conversation with Colonel House, Lloyd George, Sir Maurice Hankey, Austin Chamberlain, Arthur Balfour, 1924 June 23 (Box 52, Folder 262)
    - Conversation with Lord Grey of Fallodon, Sir William Tyrrell, J. A. Spender, Colonel House, 1924 June 27 (Box 52, Folder 263)
    - Conversation with Brand Whitlock, 1924 December 23 (Box 52, Folder 264)
    - Conversations with Sir Horace Plunkett, Sidney Brooks, H. Wickham Steed, 1925 August 1 (Box 52, Folder 265)
    - Conversation with Francis W. Hirst, 1926 October 19 (Box 52, Folder 266)
    - Conversation with S. K. Ratcliffe, 1927 March 11 (Box 52, Folder 267)
    - Conversation with General Tasker Bliss, 1928 June 22 (Box 52, Folder 268)
    - Conversation with Mr. E.S. Harkness, 1928 October 22 (Box 52, Folder 268a)
    - Conversations with Colonel House, 1935 Jan, October (Box 52, Folder 269)
    - Conversation with Colonel House re: Wilson's break with House, 1938 January 5 (Box 52, Folder 270)
  - Book Reviews
    - Histoire Diplomatique de l'Europe depuis le Congrès de Berlin jusqu'a Nos Jours. Première Partie: La Paix Armée (1878-1904) by A. Debidour. American Historical Review XXII, 3 (April 1917), pp. 655-657. (Box 53, Folder 271)
    - Charles Stewart Parnell: A Memoir by John Howard Parnell; and Charles Stewart Parnell: His Love Story and Political Life by Katherine O'Shea. Yale Review IV, 4 (July 1915), pp. 867-870. (Box 53, Folder 272)
    - The Commonwealth of Nations: an Inquiry into the Nature of Citizenship, in the British Empire, and into the Mutual Relations of the Several Communities thereof. Edited by L. Curtis. American Historical Review XXII, 3 (April 1917), pp. 644-645. (Box 53, Folder 273)
    - Tardieu versus Lansing. Yale Review X, 4 (July 1921), pp. 852-860. A review of The Truth About the Treaty by André Tardieu, and The Peace Negotiations by Robert Lansing. (Box 53, Folder 274)
    - Histoire Diplomatique de l'Europe depuis le Congrès de Berlin jusqu'a Nos Jours. Seconde Partie: Vers la Grande Guerra (1904-1916) by A. Debidour. American Historical Review XXII, 4 (July 1917), pp. 862-864. (Box 53, Folder 275)
    - "Literature of the Trenches." Yale Review VII, 3 (April 1918), pp. 632-641. A general review of 23 books on various aspects of the war. (Box 53, Folder 276)
    - The Roots of War: A Non-Technical History of Europe, 1870-1914 A. D. by William Stearns Davis, William Anderson, and Mason W. Tyler. American Historical Review XXIV, 1 (October 1918), pp. 94-96. (Box 53, Folder 277)
    - The Great European Treaties of the Nineteenth Century. Edited by Sir Augustus Oakes and by R. B. Mowat. American Historical Review XXIV, 3 (January 1919), pp. 275-276. (Box 53, Folder 278)
    - Die Politischen Geheimverträge Oestereich-Ungarns, 1879-1914, nach den Akten des Wiener Staatsarchivs and The Secret Treaties of Austria-Hungary, 1879-1914 by Alfred Franzis Pribram. American Historical Review XXV, 3 (April 1920), pp. 493-496. (Box 53, Folder 279)
    - The Economic Consequences of the Peace by John Maynard Keynes. Yale Review IX, 4 (July 1920), pp. 857-861. (Box 53, Folder 280)
    - The Inside Story of the Peace Conference by E. J. Dillon. American Historical Review XXVI, 1 (October 1920), pp. 101-102. (Box 53, Folder 281)
    - "Revolutionized Germany." Yale Review X, 2 (January 1921), pp. 418-424. A general review of five books on Germany. (Box 53, Folder 282)
    - Le Sentiment Américain pendant la Guerre by J. J. Jusserand. American Historical Review XXXVII, 2 (January 1932), pp. 339-340. (Box 53, Folder 283)
    - Woodrow Wilson as I Know Him by Joseph P. Tumulty. Literary Review (January 14, 1922). (Box 53, Folder 284)
    - The Big Four and Others of the Peace Conference by Robert Lansing. Literary Review (January 28, 1922), p. 380. (Box 53, Folder 285)
    - "Riddle of Peace Literature." Bookman LV, 4 (May 1922), pp. 229-237. A general review of eight books. (Box 53, Folder 286)
    - "Self-Criticism by the British." Yale Review XI, 4 (July 1922), pp. 869-875. A general review of six books. (Box 53, Folder 287)
    - Twenty Years, Being a Study in the Development of the Party System Between 1815-1835 by Cyril Alington. Literary Review (September 2, 1922). (Box 53, Folder 288)
    - The Life and Letters of Walter H. Page by Burton J. Hendrick. Yale Alumni Weekly XXXII, 8 (November 10, 1922), p. 210. (Box 53, Folder 289)
    - Woodrow Wilson and World Settlement by Ray Stannard Baker. Literary Review (December 16, 1922), p. 319. (Box 53, Folder 290)
    - "Three Statesmen on the War," The Bookman LVII, 6 (August 1923), pp. 642-643. A review of three books. (Box 53, Folder 291)
    - The Genesis of the War by Herbert H. Asquith. The Bookman LVIII, 4 (December 1923), pp. 479-480. (Box 53, Folder 292)
    - "The Helplessness of Europe," Literary Review IV (December 29, 1923), pp. 401-402. General review of six books. (Box 53, Folder 293)
    - Germany, France, and England by Maximilian Harden, Bookman LIX, 4 (June 1924), pp. 462-465. (Box 53, Folder 294)
    - "Questions of War Responsibility." Yale Review XIII, 4 (July 1924), pp. 790-794. A general review of three books. (Box 53, Folder 295)
    - Woodrow Wilson: A Character Study by Robert Edward Annin. Political Science Quarterly XXXIX, 4 (December 1924), pp. 684-686. (Box 53, Folder 296)
    - The Political Education of Woodrow Wilson by James Kerney. Saturday Review of Literature II (May 29, 1926), p. 280. (Box 53, Folder 297)
    - L'Autriche et la Hongrie pendant la Guerre by Bertrand Auerbach. Political Science Quarterly XLI, 2 (June 1926), pp. 298-299. (Box 53, Folder 298)
    - The New Democracy: Presidential Messages, Adresses, and Other Papers of Woodrow Wilson, 1912-1917. Edited by Ray Stannard Baker and William E. Dodd. Saturday Review of Literature III (October 16, 1926), pp. 189-190. (Box 53, Folder 299)
    - "Liberalism and the British Parliament." Yale Review XVI, 3 (April 1927), pp. 581-584. A review of Fifty Years of British Parliament by the Earl of Oxford and Asquith, and The Public Life by J. A. Spender. (Box 53, Folder 300)
    - British Documents on the Origin of the War, 1898-1914, Vol. XI: Foreign Office Documents. Edited by G. P. Gooch and Harold Temperley. Saturday Review of Literature IV (April 16, 1927), p. 730. (Box 53, Folder 301)